<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>other on Awaiting Bits</title>
    <link>https://blog.zhaytam.com/categories/other/</link>
    <description>Recent content in other on Awaiting Bits</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 10:26:06 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.zhaytam.com/categories/other/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>From Wordpress to Hugo, Self Hosting to Github Pages</title>
      <link>https://blog.zhaytam.com/2019/12/13/wordpress-to-hugo-self-hosting-to-github-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 10:26:06 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.zhaytam.com/2019/12/13/wordpress-to-hugo-self-hosting-to-github-pages/</guid>
      <description>These past months I realized that my blog, which is made using Wordpress, is very slow and that hurts the traffic. So I went looking for the problems and their solutions but nothing really worked, so I decided to switch everything.
Today I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about that decision, its advantages and disadvantages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Powerline and ZSH’s Agnoster theme in VS Code</title>
      <link>https://blog.zhaytam.com/2019/04/19/powerline-and-zshs-agnoster-theme-in-vs-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 15:50:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.zhaytam.com/2019/04/19/powerline-and-zshs-agnoster-theme-in-vs-code/</guid>
      <description>Today I was installing Oh My ZSH and the theme Agnoster and it worked in the the normal terminal but not in Visual Studio Code&amp;rsquo;s terminal, as it needs a monospaced font and Powerline isn&amp;rsquo;t one.
In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll explain how to quickly fix it.
The problem   Problem   VS Code defaults the terminal&amp;rsquo;s font to the editor&amp;rsquo;s font, and since the Agnoster theme needs Powerline, the terminal outputs non-sense characters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to lower the volume of the annoying Windows 10 notifications</title>
      <link>https://blog.zhaytam.com/2019/02/08/lower-windows-10-notifications-volume/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 19:46:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.zhaytam.com/2019/02/08/lower-windows-10-notifications-volume/</guid>
      <description>I bought a laptop a long time ago but I never really used it enough to notice this.
I am now using it every day and every time a Windows 10 notification shows up, both my ears bleed (not really but you get the idea).
The volume of these notifications is EXTREMELY loud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Newborn blog – What’s it about? – Hello World!</title>
      <link>https://blog.zhaytam.com/2018/06/22/newborn-blog-hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 04:43:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.zhaytam.com/2018/06/22/newborn-blog-hello-world/</guid>
      <description>Hello,
Since Awaiting bits is a newborn blog, I decided to take this opportunity to present myself as well as the purpose of this blog.
About me My name is Zanid Haytam and I was born in 1997.
I have been programming since the age of 13 and never looked back since.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://blog.zhaytam.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.zhaytam.com/about/</guid>
      <description>TODO</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
